Contact

theobaidur@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/theobaidur (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Front-End Development
Full-Stack Development
Python (Programming Language)

Languages English

Obaidur Rahman

Full Stack Web Developer | Microsoft Dynamics 365 Developer | Browser Extension Developer

Mirpur, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Summary

11+ years of experience in IT (Software Development) industry, graduation (BSC) in Computer Science and Engineering and post graduation (MSC) in Computer Science. I have got extensive experience in full stack web development, database design and development, Microsoft Dynamics 365, and others. I am passionate with JavaScript, Typescript, React, Angular, Vue, NodeJs, etc.

Frontend Technologies

- * JavaScript
- * Typescript
- * React
- * Angular
- * Vue
- * Browser/Chrome Extensions
- * HTML
- * CSS, SCSS, SASS, LESS, etc.

Backend Technologies

- * NodeJs
- * Express
- * NestJs
- * PHP
- * Laravel
- * Lumen

Databases and ORM

- * Relational Database (MySQL, PostgreSQL, etc.)
- * NoSQL Database (MongoDB, Firebase, etc.)
- * ORM (Sequelize, TypeORM, Prisma, Mongoose, etc.)

Microsoft Dynamics 365

- * Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Customer Service
- * Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Field Service

- * PowerApps, Model Driven Apps, Canvas Apps, Workflow, Business Rules, etc.
- * Writing Custom Plugins, Custom Workflow Activities, Custom Actions, etc. using C# and .NET
- * Writing Custom JavaScript Functions and Custom Web Resources
- * Writing custom Applications using Microsoft Dynamics 365 SDKs, Web API, OData, etc.
- * Integrating Microsoft Dynamics 365 with other systems using Web API, OData, etc.
- * Integrating Microsoft Dynamics 365 with SharePoint using SharePoint APIs

Cloud infrastructure

- * AWS (EC2, S3, Lambda, etc.)
- * Azure (Web Apps, Functions, Blob Storage, etc.)
- * Digital Ocean (Droplets, Spaces, etc.)

Hands on Experience

- * Python (Django, Flask, etc.)
- * C# (.NET)
- * ASP.NET (MVC, Web API, etc.)

Other Skills

- * ServiceNow Development
- * Mobile App Development using React Native, Ionic, etc.
- * Desktop App Development using Electron.js, etc.

Version Control

- * Git
- * GitHub
- * BitBucket
- * Azure DevOps

Project Management

- * Jira
- * Trello
- * Azure DevOps
- * GitHub Projects

* BitBucket Projects

Editors

- * Visual Studio Code
- * Visual Studio
- * Sublime Text
- * WebStorm
- * PhpStorm, etc.

Communication Tools

- * Emails
- * Slack
- * Microsoft Teams
- * Skype
- * Zoom
- * Google Meet

Design Tools

- * Adobe Photoshop
- * Figma

Links

- * GitHub Profile https://github.com/theobaidur
- * StackOverflow Profile https://stackoverflow.com/users/8145467/ obie

Experience

Concourse Federal Group Software Engineer June 2018 - Present (4 years 4 months)

Call and Solution
Sr. Front End Developer
October 2017 - Present (5 years)

Working as Sr. Front End Developer based on angular 1.5.x.

Diva World Wide Sr. Web Developer March 2017 - Present (5 years 7 months) Page 3 of 4 Badda, Dhaka

Raire Software
Frontend Developer
September 2014 - February 2016 (1 year 6 months)
USA

Elance-oDesk
Freelance Web Developer
April 2013 - September 2014 (1 year 6 months)

Valence Systems
Frontend Developer
January 2012 - February 2013 (1 year 2 months)

Webasia teach Junior Web Developer August 2011 - January 2012 (6 months) Dhaka, Bangladesh

Education

Jahangirnagar University

Masters in CSE, Computer Science and Engineering · (2019 - 2021)

University of Asia Pacific

Bachelor of Computer Science and Engineering, Computer Science · (January 2012 - February 2016)

BCIC College

Higher Secondary School Certificate (HSC), Science · (2009 - 2011)

Baitul Mosharraf Senior Madrasa Secondary School Certificate (SSC/Dakhil) · (2007 - 2009)